<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Jurassic Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="located">Located:  </string>
    <string name="threat_level">Threat Level:  </string>
    <string name="weight">WEIGHT:  </string>
    <string name="length">LENGTH:  </string>
    <string name="discovered">YEAR DISCOVERED:  </string>
    <string name="character_details">Character Details: </string>
    <string name="films_appeared">Films Appeared: </string>
    <string name="role_in_films">Role in Films: </string>
    <string name="portrayed_by" translatable="false">Portrayed By: </string>
    <string name="character_name">Character Name</string>
    <string name="choose_your_location">CHOOSE A LOCATION</string>

    <!-- Loading Screen Messages-->
    <string-array name="textMessages">
        <item name="0">Don\'t go into the long grass\!</item>
        <item name="1">Oh, yeah. Oooh, ahhh, that\'s how it always starts. Then later there\'s running and um, screaming.</item>
        <item name="2">Don\'t move. He won\'t see us if we don\'t move…</item>
        <item name="3">…Just follow the screams.</item>
        <item name="4">Did you read Malcolm\'s book?</item>
        <item name="5">That thing out there… That is no dinosaur.</item>
        <item name="6">Welcome to Jurassic Park</item>
    </string-array>
    <!-- Dinosaur Names-->
    <string name="Tyranosaurus_rex">Tyranosaurus Rex</string>
    <string name="Stegosaurus">Stegosaurus</string>
    <string name="Velociraptor">Velociraptor</string>
    <string name="Triceratops">Triceratops</string>
    <string name="Parasaurolophus">Parasaurolophus</string>
    <string name="Gallimimus">Gallimimus</string>
    <string name="Dilophosaurus">Dilophosaurus</string>
    <string name="Compsognathus">Compsognathus</string>
    <string name="Brachiosaurus">Brachiosaurus</string>
    <string name="Pachycephalosaurus">Pachycephalosaurus</string>
    <string name="Pteranodon">Pteranodon</string>
    <string name="Ankylosaurus">Ankylosaurus</string>
    <string name="Apatosaurus">Apatosaurus</string>
    <string name="Dimorphodon">Dimorphodon</string>
    <string name="Spinosaurus">Spinosaurus</string>
    <string name="Indominous_Rex">Indominus Rex</string>
    <string name="Mosasaurus">Mosasaurus</string>
    <!-- Dinosaur Period-->
    <string name="Late_Cretaceous">Late Cretaceous</string>
    <string name="Early_Jurassic">Early Jurassic</string>
    <string name="Late_Jurassic">Late Jurassic</string>
    <string name="Mid_Cretaceous">Mid Cretaceous</string>
    <!-- Dinosaur Classification-->
    <string name="Carnivore">Carnivore</string>
    <string name="Herbivore">Herbivore</string>
    <string name="Omnivore">Omnivore</string>
    <!-- Dinosaur Details-->
    <string name="trex_hunter">The T. Rex is one of the most dangerous hunters from the age of the dinosaurs.</string>
    <string name="Spinosaurus_fact">The large sail along the Spinosaurus\' back may have been for heat dissipation, as it lived primarily in swampy areas near the equator.</string>
    <string name="Steg_fact">The Stegasaurus had 17 bony plates along it\'s back and tail in two rows.</string>
    <string name="Velociraptor_fact">The Velociraptor had a sharp, sickle-shaped retractable claw on each foot.</string>
    <string name="Triceratops_fact">When threatened, the Triceratops charged into its enemy like modern the Rhinoceros.</string>
    <string name="Para_fact">The bony crest on the Parasaurolophus\' head, is believed to have helped the dinosaur make a low-frequency, fog-horn-like sound.</string>
    <string name="gallimimus_fact">The Gallimimus was a fast-moving, bird-like dinosaur with a toothless beak.</string>
    <string name="Diloph_fact">The Dilophosaurus was a fast predator, whom in the film is depicted as spitting poison - but there is no fossil evidence of this.</string>
    <string name="Compy_fact">The Compsognathus is the smallest known dinosaur, and was about the size of a chicken.</string>
    <string name="Pteranodon_fact">The Pteranodon was actually a flying reptile, and technically not a dinosaur.</string>
    <string name="Brach_fact">The Brachiosaurus\' front legs were longer than it\'s rear, giving it the name \"Arm Lizard\"</string>
    <string name="Anky_fact">The Ankylosaurus was a tank-like dinosaur. It\'s entire top was covered with thick, oval plates fused into it\'s leathery skin. It also had two rows of spikes along it\'s body, horns and a club-like tail.</string>
    <string name="Apat_fact">Also called \"Brontosaurus\", this large dinosaur would swallow large stones to help grind up it\'s tough plant diet since it did not chew it\'s food.</string>
    <string name="Pachy_fact">The Pachycephalosaurus had an incredibly thick skull (10 inches). It\'s believed that this dinosaur used their hard skulls in intra-species combat as well as a defense mechanism.</string>
    <string name="Dimorph_fact">The Dimorphodon gets it\'s name from the Greek for Two Teeth, because it had two distinct shapes of teeth in its jaw - which is incredibly rare among reptiles</string>
    <string name="Mos_fact">The Mosasaurus was one of the largest aquatic reptiles during the time of the dinosaurs. This creature likely lived near the ocean surface and ate anything that approached the water.</string>
    <string name="Indom_fact">The Indominus Rex was a genectically modified hybrid. The base genomes consisted of Tyrannosaurus Rex, Gigantosaurus, Velociraptors, Pit Vipers among several other modern creatures.</string>

    <!-- Dinosaur Measurements-->
    <string name="Feet_30">30 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_40">40 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_6">6 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_15">15 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_20">20 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_80">80 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_4_Inch_28">28 Inches - 4 Feet</string>
    <string name="Wingspan_30_Feet">30 Feet (Wingspan)</string>
    <string name="Feet_40Plus">40+ Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_16">16 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_70">70+ Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_50">50 Feet</string>
    <string name="Feet_4_Wingspan">4+ Feet (Wingspan)</string>
    <string name="Lbs_30000">30,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_65000">65,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_8000">8,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_20">20+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_900">900 Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_6000">6,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_25000">25,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_12000">12,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_10000">10,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_6">6 Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_55">55 Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_1000">1000 Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_64000">64,000+ Lbs</string>
    <string name="Lbs_700">700 Lbs</string>

    <!-- Dinosaur Discovery-->
    <string name="Year_1905">1905</string>
    <string name="Year_1922">1922</string>
    <string name="Year_1822">1822</string>
    <string name="Year_2012">2012</string>
    <string name="Year_1924">1924</string>
    <string name="Year_1889">1889</string>
    <string name="Year_1972">1972</string>
    <string name="Year_1903">1903</string>
    <string name="Year_1970">1970</string>
    <string name="Year_1876">1876</string>
    <string name="Year_1938">1938</string>
    <string name="Year_1915">1915</string>
    <string name="Year_1908">1908</string>
    <string name="Year_1877">1877</string>
    <string name="Year_1859">1859</string>
    <!-- People Names-->
    <string name="Bryce_Dallas_Howard">Bryce Dallas Howard</string>
    <string name="Clarie_Dearing">Claire Dearing</string>
    <string name="Fact_Claire">As Jurassic World\'s work-aholic operations manager, Claire is seen initially as part of the problem, since she only sees the dinosaurs as an attraction rather than a living, breathing creature. Through her time in the film, she begins to realize that there is more to life than her position at Jurassic World, after her two visiting nephews become lost in the park after the Indominus Rex escapes.</string>
    <string name="Chris_Pratt">Chris Pratt</string>
    <string name="Owen_Grady">Owen Grady</string>
    <string name="Fact_Owen">Owen is introduced as an on-site staff at Jurassic World. Formerly in the United States Navy, Owen currently conducts behavioral research on the parks pack of Velociraptors. Owen has trained the raptors since they hatched thus he was able to imprint on them and has created personal relationships with them -specifically on the pack leader \'Blue\'. Owen criticizes the genetic modification of the dinosaurs, and openly disagrees with the paddock design of Indominus Rex.</string>
    <string name="Alessandro_Nivola">Alessandro Nivola</string>
    <string name="Billy_Brennan">Billy Brennan</string>
    <string name="Fact_Billy">Billy is an overenthusiastic graduate student who works at Dr. Grant\'s dig site in the third film. Billy accompanies Dr. Grant on the expedition to Isla Sorna, and while there decides to steal a collection of Velociraptor eggs in the hopes that he could sell them to help fund Dr. Grant\'s dig. Although his actions were noble in his mind, it caused the Raptors to trap the group in order to retrieve the eggs.</string>
    <string name="William_H_Macy">William H. Macy</string>
    <string name="Paul_Kirby">Paul Kirby</string>
    <string name="Fact_Paul">Mr. Kirby, along with his ex-wife, Amanda, pose as a wealthy couple to lure Dr. Grant onto Isla Sorna under the facade of a sight-seeing aerial tour. Ultimately, Paul\'s goal is to land on the island in search of his missing son. After the group is attacked by a Spinosaurus on the river, Paul uses himself as bait so the others can escape. Although he finds his son, they all barely survive the island if not for the actions of Dr. Satler who sends in the US Navy and Marines when she receives a call from Dr. Grant on a sat-phone and hears a dinosaur roar.</string>
    <string name="Richard_Attenborough">Richard Attenborough</string>
    <string name="John_Hammond">John Hammond</string>
    <string name="Fact_Hammond">John Hammond is the founder of InGen, and believes that his dream of creating a park that encourages every attendee to stop in wonder and awe of the scientific reality of dinosaurs walking on the earth again. Hammond is a kind, jovial and charismatic individual. Although his intent seemed to be pure-of-heart, his vision turned out to be a truly dangerous idea.</string>
    <string name="B_D_Wong">B.D. Wong</string>
    <string name="Dr_Henry_Wu">Dr. Henry Wu</string>
    <string name="Fact_Wu">Dr. Wu was the chief genetic engineer in Jurassic Park, and takes great pride in what he has accomplished. After the havoc on Isla Nublar, he believes that there simply not enough control. He felt that when the dinosaurs proved to be breeding on the island, that was a \"tremendous validation of his work.\" It\'s this belief that motivates Dr. Wu to further his research in Jurassic World and eventually engineer the Indominus Rex.</string>
    <string name="Jeff_Goldblum">Jeff Goldblum</string>
    <string name="Dr_Malcolm">Dr. Ian Malcolm</string>
    <string name="Fact_Malcolm">Dr. Malcolm is one of the main characters in the first films, and acts as the ironic commentator through much of the films. He is a brilliant mathematician who specialized in chaos theory. Based on \'chaos theory\' Malcolm is able to make several predictions about the inherent dangers and ultimate failures of trying to control nature through genetic power.</string>
    <string name="Laura_Dern">Laura Dern</string>
    <string name="Dr_Satler">Dr. Ellie Satler</string>
    <string name="Fact_Satler">Dr. Satler is a Paleobotanist who is introduced with Dr. Grant in Montana. In the first film Dr. Satler learns that the team behind Jurassic Park hadn\'t actually taken into consideration how the island itself wasn\'t habitable for the dinosaurs they created, as some of the plant life was actually toxic.</string>
    <string name="Sam_Neill">Sam Neill</string>
    <string name="Dr_Grant">Dr. Alan Grant</string>
    <string name="Fact_Grant">Dr. Grant was first introduced as an archaeologist in Montana digging for Velociraptor fossils. He is approached by John Hammond in an attempt to have Dr. Grant sign off on the unbelievable Jurassic Park. Through the series of films, Dr. Grant transitions from wide-eyed awe to much more cynical and standoffish.</string>

    <string name="Antagonist">Antagonist</string>
    <string name="Protagonist">Protagonist</string>
    <string name="Bystander_Antagonist">Bystander / Antagonist</string>

    <!-- Location Names-->
    <string name="Brach_enclosure">Brachiosaurus Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_Central">Isla Nublar - Central</string>
    <string name="Gall_enclosure">Gallimimus Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_South">Isla Nublar - South</string>
    <string name="Triceratops_enclosure">Triceratops Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Para_enclosure">Parasaurolophus Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Rex_enclosure">Tyrannosaurus Rex Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_East">Isla Nublar - East</string>
    <string name="Raptor_enclosure">Velociraptor Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_West_Compound">Isla Nublar - West (Main Compound)</string>
    <string name="Diloph_enclosure">Dilophosaurus Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_West">Isla Nublar - West</string>
    <string name="Herr_enclosure">Herrerasaurus Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Bary_enclosure">Baryonyx Enclosure</string>
    <string name="Vis_Center">Visitor Center</string>
    <string name="Port">Port</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_North_East"><![CDATA[Isla Nublar - North & East]]></string>
    <string name="Helipad">Helipad</string>

    <!-- Film Appearance Validation-->
    <string name="jurassic_park_one">Jurassic Park</string>
    <string name="jurassic_park_two">Jurassic Park Two</string>
    <string name="jurassic_park_three">Jurassic Park Three</string>
    <string name="jurassic_world">Jurassic World</string>
    <string name="One_world">One, World</string>
    <string name="Two_world">Two, World</string>
    <string name="One_two_three_world">One, Two, Three, World</string>
    <string name="One_World_Fallen">One, World, Fallen</string>
    <string name="One_Two_Fallen">One, Two, Fallen</string>
    <string name="One_two_world">One, Two, World</string>
    <string name="One_Three">One, Three</string>
    <string name="Two_three">Two, Three</string>
    <string name="Two_three_world">Two, Three, World</string>
    <string name="World_fallen">World, Fallen</string>
    <string name="One_two">One, Two</string>
    <string name="Three_world">Three, World</string>
    <string name="Movie_Only">Movie Only - Not Real</string>
    <string name="Unknown">Unknown</string>
    <string name="World_validation">World</string>
    <string name="Fallen_validation">Fallen</string>
    <string name="One_validation">One</string>
    <string name="Two_validation">Two</string>
    <string name="Three_validation">Three</string>
    <string name="Jurassic_World">Jurassic World</string>
    <string name="The_Lost_World">The Lost World</string>
    <string name="Jurassic_Park">Jurassic Park</string>

    <!-- Incident Details-->
    <string name="Isla_Nublar_Incident">Isla Nublar Incident</string>
    <string name="Robert_Muldoon">Robert Muldoon</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_Containment_Pen">Isla Nublar - Containment Pen</string>
    <string name="Incident_Nublar_Details">Due to the growing number of incidents involving the park\'s Velociraptors; it was decided that they would be moved from an open paddock to the more structurally sound Velociraptor Pen in the Main Compound. During the move, late at night while transplanting the largest of the raptors the crate where the Raptor was confined was jostled and Jophery was pulled inside by the raptor.</string>
    <string name="T_Rex_Incident">Tyrannasaurus Escape</string>
    <string name="Grant_Murphy_Malcolm">Dr. Alan Grant, Tim Murphy, Lex Murphy, Dr. Ian Malcolm</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_Rex_Paddock">Isla Nublar - Tyrannasaurus Paddock</string>
    <string name="Incident_Rex_Paddock_Details">Due to Dennis Nedry\'s industrial sabotage, Jurassic Park\'s security is crippled and all of the main systems are taken offline. While the system is down most of the perimiter and paddock fences are taken offline, leaving them un-electrified. During this time while the visiting team is trapped within their jeeps, the Tyrannasaur crashes through his paddock fence.</string>
    <string name="Dilop_Incident">Dilophosaurus Attack</string>
    <string name="Dennis_Nedry">Dennis Nedry</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_Access_Rd">Isla Nublar - Access Road</string>
    <string name="Incident_Diloph_Details">While attempting to escape Jurassic Park with his theft of dozens of Dinosaur Embryos, Dennis Nedry becomes lost as a massive storm whips through the park. Nedry slips and falls down a rocky waterfall before encountering a couple Dilophosaurs who have surrounded him. As he thinks that he has escaped he finds that one of the Dilophosaurs has climbed into his Jeep. He is attacked while the canister of Embryos is buried in the silt and gravel.</string>
    <string name="Compy_Incident">Compsognathus Attack</string>
    <string name="Bowman_Family">Bowman Family</string>
    <string name="Isla_N_Coast">Isla Sorna - Coast</string>
    <string name="Incident_Compy_Details">While sailing on a family yacht, the Bowman family is vacationing on the beach. While her parents are enjoying the sun and sand, Cindy wanders across the beach with her sandwich before stumbling upon a friendly looking Compsognathus. She offers some of her food to which the Compy eats before a dozen more Compy\'s appear and attack her.</string>
    <string name="Sorna_Rescue_Incident">Rescue on Isla Sorna</string>
    <string name="Malcolm_Harding_Carr_Owen">Dr. Ian Malcolm, Dr. Sarah Harding, Eddie Carr, Nick Van Owen</string>
    <string name="Isla_S">Isla Sorna</string>
    <string name="Incident_Rescue_Sorna">After meeting with a bed-ridden John Hammond, Dr. Malcolm learns that ownership of InGen has passed to Hammond\'s nephew, Peter Ludlow. As a last ditch effort to catalog and research how the dinosaurs on \'site b\' were able to survive, Hammond explains that Sarah Harding has already left for the island. Malcolm joins the expedition that Hammond intended to create, but declares that this will be a rescue mission rather than a research trip.</string>
    <string name="Rex_Capture_Incident">Capturing the Tyrannasaurus</string>
    <string name="Ludlow_Tembo_Malcolm">Peter Ludlow, Roland Tembo, Dr. Ian Malcolm</string>
    <string name="Isla_S_Central">Isla Sorna - Central</string>
    <string name="Incident_Rex_Capture_Details">Opposed to John Hammond\'s research expedition, Peter Ludlow, the new CEO of InGen decides to exploit the surviving dinosaurs on Isla Sorna so that InGen doesn\'t go bankrupt. Ludlow puts together a team of hunters and trackers to catalog and capture dozens of dinosaurs with the goal of returning them to a new park being built in San Diego. While on the hunt, Roland tracks and eventually captures the mighty Tyrannasaurus Rex.</string>
    <string name="San_Diego_Incident">Havoc in San Diego</string>
    <string name="Malcolm_Harding">Dr. Ian Malcolm, Sarah Harding</string>
    <string name="San_Diego_California">San Diego, California</string>
    <string name="Incident_San_Diego_Details">After capturing the Tyrannasaurus Rex, Ludlow has the carnivorous monster transported to the United States with the intent of it being the star attraction at the new park in San Diego. Yet, Ludlow\'s ship had a few problems while out at sea, and it appears that the T. Rex had awoken from it\'s drug-induced sleep and attacked the crew. Although it was trapped below deck, it was inadvertently released and began rampaging through the streets of San Diego.</string>
    <string name="New_Species_Incident">New Species Bred</string>
    <string name="Unnamed_InGen">Unnamed InGen Scientists</string>
    <string name="Jurassic_Three">Jurassic Park III</string>
    <string name="Incident_New_Species">In secret, several dinosaurs were bred and cloned on Isla Sorna. These cloning experiments where entirely illegal, as the Gene Guard Act was passed a few months earlier. In direct violation of the law, the scientists bred dinosaurs like Ankylosaurus, Ceratosaurus, Corythosaurus and Spinosaurus. These dinosaurs are bred without consent from InGen or the new owner Masrani Global - but rather directed by Henry Wu.</string>
    <string name="JW_Planning_Incident">Jurassic World Planning</string>
    <string name="Simon_Masrani">Simon Masrani</string>
    <string name="Masrani_Global">Masrani Global</string>
    <string name="Incident_World_Planning">After Masrani Global offers InGen a corporate buy out, Simon Masrani declares that his old friend, John Hammond, would have wanted him to bring his dream to fruition by developing and building Jurassic World. Thus the planning and conceptual designs are started.</string>
    <string name="E_Kirby_Rescue_Incident">Rescue of Eric Kirby</string>
    <string name="Grant_EKirby_PKirby">Dr. Alan Grant, Eric Kirby, Peter Kirby</string>
    <string name="Incident_Rescue_Kirby_Details">After Eric survives a crash landing on Isla Sorna while on a parasailing adventure with his step-father, Ben, a rescue mission is created and Dr. Grant is tricked into joining the expedition. Erik\'s parents, now separated, decide that they need to get to the island at all costs. After the plane lands, it\'s discovered that there are even more dangerous things on this island.</string>
    <string name="Raptor_incident">Hunted by Velociraptors</string>
    <string name="Grant_Brennan">Dr. Alan Grant, Billy Brennan</string>
    <string name="Incident_Raptor_Hunt_Details">After being stranded on the island after their plane crashes through the jungle, Billy finds a nest of Velociraptor eggs and thinks that he could help Dr. Grant\'s dig site by bringing them home and selling them. Although his intentions had slight nobility to them, it caused the pack of raptors to track and trap the team in a clearing. It appears as though all they want are the eggs, so Dr. Grant returns the eggs freely.</string>
    <string name="World_New_Dino_Incident">Jurassic World Has New Dinosaurs</string>
    <string name="Isla_N">Isla Nublar</string>
    <string name="Incident_New_Dino_Details">After jumping through several hoops, and getting the Gene Guard Act re-written, Masrani Global is allowed to breed new dinosaurs. During this process the dinosaurs from Isla Sorna are transported to Isla Nublar. Now as the park is finally completed, Masrani begins the process of creating new attractions under the supervision of Dr. Henry Wu.</string>
    <string name="Hybrid_Incident">The Birth of a Hybrid</string>
    <string name="Incident_Hybrid_Details">Through several attempts at genetic modification, Dr. Wu has been given full authorization to breed hybrid dinosaurs to bring new life and visitors to the park. During Dr. Wu\'s experiments, the Indominus Rex is hatched. The Indominus was genetical modified from Gigantosaurus, Tyrannosaurus Rex, Velociraptor, Pit Vipers, Tree Frogs, Cuttlefish, and an unidentified number of modern animals.</string>
    <string name="Jurassic_World_Incident">Jurassic World Incident</string>
    <string name="Grady_Dearing">Owen Grady, Claire Dearing</string>
    <string name="Incident_World_Details">After requesting Owen\'s input on any potential flaws in Paddock 11, Owen and Claire fear that the Indominus Rex had climbed out of the paddock, only to discover that the I.Rex had a sort of active camoflauge and could hide itself from heat-vision. While Owen escapes, the I.Rex does as well and begins searching for more food.</string>
    <string name="FromMovie_Intent_String">FromMovie</string>

    <string name="Space_Jurassic_Park">  Jurassic Park</string>
    <string name="Space_The_Lost_World">  The Lost World: Jurassic Park</string>
    <string name="Space_Jurassic_Three">  Jurassic Park III</string>
    <string name="Space_Jurassic_World">  Jurassic World</string>
    <string name="Space_World_Fallen_Kingdom">  Jurassic World: Fallen Kingdom</string>
    <string name="Card_Details_Tag">EXTRA_CARD_MODEL</string>
</resources>